<Documentation>
	<General/>
	<SPARROW_model>
		<SPARROW_papers>
			<Paper id="paper">
				<Link link="http://water.usgs.gov/nawqa/sparrow/wrr97/results.html"/>
				<Citation_mods>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<genre/>
					<titleInfo>
						<title>SPARROW Surface Water-Quality Modeling Nutrients in Watersheds of the Coterminous United States</title>
					</titleInfo>
					<originInfo>
						<dateOther>1997-01-01 00:00:00.0</dateOther>
						<publisher>Apress</publisher>
						<placeTerm/>
					</originInfo>
					<name>
						<namePart>Smith, R.A., G.E. Schwarz, and R.B. Alexander</namePart>
						<role>Author</role>
					</name>
					<physicalDescription>
						<form/>
						<form/>
						<form/>
					</physicalDescription>
					<note type="citation/reference">Smith, R.A. et al. 1997. SPARROW Surface Water-Quality Modeling Nutrients in Watersheds of the Coterminous United States. Regional interpretation of water-quality monitoring data, Water Resources Research, v. 33, no. 12, pp.2781-2798</note>
					<edition/>
					<languageTerm>ENGLISH</languageTerm>
				</Citation_mods>
			</Paper>
			<Paper id="factsheet">
				<Link link="http://pubs.usgs.gov/fs/2009/3019/pdf/fs_2009_3019.pdf"/>
				<Citation_mods>
					<identifier type="">myid</identifier>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<genre/>
					<titleInfo>
						<title>SPARROW MODELING - Enhancing Understanding of the Nation's Water Quality</title>
					</titleInfo>
					<originInfo>
						<dateOther>2009-03-01 00:00:00.0</dateOther>
						<publisher>U.S. Geological Survey</publisher>
						<placeTerm/>
					</originInfo>
					<name>
						<namePart>Preston, S.D., Alexander, R.B., Woodside, M.D., and Hamilton, P.A.</namePart>
						<role>Author</role>
					</name>
					<physicalDescription>
						<form/>
						<form/>
						<form/>
					</physicalDescription>
					<note type="citation/reference">Preston, S.D., Alexander, R.B., Woodside, M.D., and Hamilton, P.A., 2009, SPARROW MODELING-Enhancing Understanding of the Nation's Water Quality: U.S. Geological Survey Fact Sheet 2009-3019, 6 p.</note>
					<edition/>
					<languageTerm>ENGLISH</languageTerm>
				</Citation_mods>
			</Paper>
		</SPARROW_papers>
	</SPARROW_model>
	<CommonTerms>
		<Term id="MRB">
			<p>The US is divided into 8 major river basins: New England and Mid-Atlantic; South Atlantic-Gulf and Tennessee; Great Lakes, Ohio, Upper Mississippi and Souris-Red-Rainy; Missouri; Lower Mississippi, Arkansas-White-Red and Texas-Gulf; Rio Grande, Colorado and Great Basin; Pacific Northwest; and California.</p>
		</Term>
		<Term id="Data Series">
			<p>The <em>Data Series</em> specifies what data is drawn on the map.
			The most common model output is the <em>Total Instream Flux</em>,
			which is the average amount of the constituent you would expect to
			find in a stream, as predicted by the model.</p>
			<p>The complete of data series:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Total Instream Flux</b><br/>
					The average daily load of the constituent leaving each
					stream reach, as predicted by the model.
					This is also called the <i>measurable flux</i> since
					this is the hypothetical value you could measure in the
					stream, if there was a way to measure daily average.
				</li>
                <li><b>Incremental Flux</b><br/>
					The average daily load of the constituent added at each
					stream reach.  Or, the amount of load that each reach is
					responsible for contributing to the river system.
					The presented value is not 'decayed' by travel down
					the reach.
                </li>
                <li><b>Incremental Yield</b><br/>
                	The <i>Incremental Flux</i> divided by the drainage area of
                	the reach.
                </li>
                <li><b>Concentration</b><br/>
                	The <i>Total Instream Flux</i> divided by the average daily
                	flow of the reach.
                </li>
                <li><b>Source Value</b><br/>
                	The source value is the amount of a particular source
                	added in the reaches drainage area - you must choose a
                	source when you choose this data series.  If you have created
                	adjustments as part of a 'what if' scenario, the adjusted
                	source values are presented. 
                </li>
                <li><b>Delivery Fraction</b><br/>
                	The fraction of the load leaving a reach that arrives at the
                	downstream end of a selected target reach.  You must choose
                	a target reach if you select this series.
                </li>
                <li><b>Incremental Delivered Flux</b><br/>Not currently supported</li>
                <li><b>Total Delivered Flux</b><br/>Not currently supported</li>
                <li><b>Incremental Delivered Yield</b><br/>Not currently supported</li>
                <li><b>Total Standard Err Estimate</b><br/>
                	An estimate of error, based on the model, of the
                	<i>Total Instream Flux</i>.  This is only an estimate and should
                	not be used for any purpose.
                	For actual error values, contact the hydrologist for the model.
                </li>
                <li><b>Incremental Standard Err Estimate</b><br/>
                    An estimate of error, based on the model, of the
                	<i>Incremental Flux</i>.  This is only an estimate and should
                	not be used for any purpose.
                	For actual error values, contact the hydrologist for the model.
                </li>
			</ul>
		</Term>
		<Term id="Total">
			Takes into account constituent sources upstream and degradation to describe the annual load of the constituent being transported by national surface waters. Units are typically kilograms/year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental">
			Takes into account only sources of the constituent within the surrounding catchment to show local generation of the constituent independent of the upstream load. Units are typically kilograms/year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental Yield">
			Takes into account only sources of the constituent within the surrounding catchment to show the local generation of the constituent normalized for catchment area. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Concentration">
			Total load divided by the long-term average flow of the stream reach. Units are typically kilograms/cubic feet.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Source Value">
			Displays the location and frequency of constituent sources. Units are typically kilograms/year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Delivery Fraction">
			Displays the fraction of incremental load that is delivered to a target reach of interest.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental Delivered Flux">
			Displays the incremental flux generated by a catchment that is delivered to a target reach of interest. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Total Delivered Flux">
			Displays the total flux including sources upstream and within the catchment that is delivered to a target reach of interest. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental Delivered Yield">
			Displays the incremental yield that is delivered to a target reach of interest. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="For Source">
			Each model has different sources that were determined by statistically significant by the modeler.
			Choose a constituent source from the list to present data only from that source.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Comparison">
			For the selected <i>Data Series</i>, the result generated by your
			adjusted values can be compared to the result of the unadjusted model.
			Two options are available:
			<ul>
			<li><b>Absolute change from nominal</b> subtracts the
			nominal (unadjusted) model result from the adjusted model result.</li>
			<li><b>% change from nominal</b> presents the percent increase of
			the adjusted model result over the nominal model result.  That is:<br/>
			<code>100 X (adjusted - nominal) / nominal</code><br/>
			Any increase from a nominal value of zero is considered a 100% change.
			Any decrease from a nominal value of zero is considered a -100% change.</li>
			</ul>
		</Term>
		<Term id="Nominal">
			The nominal SPARROW DSS model condition is based on source values and streamflow of the model base year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Bins">
			The bins determine how values grouped and displayed on the map.
			For instance, you might	create bins 0-10 and 10-100 and
			have the values in the 0-10 bin colored grey and values in the 10-100
			bin colored as red.
			Two auto-generation options are available:
			<ul>
			<li><b>Equal Count</b> attempts to construct bins such that an equal
			number of data values fall within each bin.  Because the values
			are sometimes clustered, it is often not possible to generate bins
			with an even distribution of values into each bin.</li>
			<li><b>Equal Range</b> construct bins such that each bin has an
			equal size or range.</li>
			</ul>
			You must define bins before a map is generated.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Map Options">
			Controls basic features of how the map is rendered.
			Click the headings of the subsections for more information on each feature.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Reach">
			Stream segments that extend between confluence with other streams.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Catchment">
			A watershed that drains to a single stream.
		</Term>
		<Term id="HUC">
			Hydrologic Unit Code
		</Term>
		<Term id="Aggregate Function">
			Calculates the average, maximum, minimum, or sum of the model output when the map displays over HUC.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Reaches Or Catchments">
			Selecting 'Reaches' will draw individual reach lines on the map.
			Selecting 'Catchments' will draw the filled polygons of each catchment.
			In both cases, the color used to render the reach or catchment is based
			on the binning selection under the 'What to map' section.
		</Term>
	</CommonTerms>
</Documentation>
