<Documentation>
	<General/>
	<SPARROW_model>
		<SPARROW_papers>
			<Paper id="paper">
				<Link link="http://water.usgs.gov/nawqa/sparrow/wrr97/results.html"/>
				<Citation_mods>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<genre/>
					<titleInfo>
						<title>SPARROW Surface Water-Quality Modeling Nutrients in Watersheds of the Coterminous United States</title>
					</titleInfo>
					<originInfo>
						<dateOther>1997-01-01 00:00:00.0</dateOther>
						<publisher>Apress</publisher>
						<placeTerm/>
					</originInfo>
					<name>
						<namePart>Smith, R.A., G.E. Schwarz, and R.B. Alexander</namePart>
						<role>Author</role>
					</name>
					<physicalDescription>
						<form/>
						<form/>
						<form/>
					</physicalDescription>
					<note type="citation/reference">Smith, R.A. et al. 1997. SPARROW Surface Water-Quality Modeling Nutrients in Watersheds of the Coterminous United States. Regional interpretation of water-quality monitoring data, Water Resources Research, v. 33, no. 12, pp.2781-2798</note>
					<edition/>
					<languageTerm>ENGLISH</languageTerm>
				</Citation_mods>
			</Paper>
			<Paper id="factsheet">
				<Link link="http://pubs.usgs.gov/fs/2009/3019/pdf/fs_2009_3019.pdf"/>
				<Citation_mods>
					<identifier type="">myid</identifier>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<genre/>
					<titleInfo>
						<title>SPARROW MODELING - Enhancing Understanding of the Nation's Water Quality</title>
					</titleInfo>
					<originInfo>
						<dateOther>2009-03-01 00:00:00.0</dateOther>
						<publisher>U.S. Geological Survey</publisher>
						<placeTerm/>
					</originInfo>
					<name>
						<namePart>Preston, S.D., Alexander, R.B., Woodside, M.D., and Hamilton, P.A.</namePart>
						<role>Author</role>
					</name>
					<physicalDescription>
						<form/>
						<form/>
						<form/>
					</physicalDescription>
					<note type="citation/reference">Preston, S.D., Alexander, R.B., Woodside, M.D., and Hamilton, P.A., 2009, SPARROW MODELING-Enhancing Understanding of the Nation's Water Quality: U.S. Geological Survey Fact Sheet 2009-3019, 6 p.</note>
					<edition/>
					<languageTerm>ENGLISH</languageTerm>
				</Citation_mods>
			</Paper>
		</SPARROW_papers>
	</SPARROW_model>
	<CommonTerms>
		<Term id="MRB">
			<p>The US is divided into 8 major river basins: New England and Mid-Atlantic; South Atlantic-Gulf and Tennessee; Great Lakes, Ohio, Upper Mississippi and Souris-Red-Rainy; Missouri; Lower Mississippi, Arkansas-White-Red and Texas-Gulf; Rio Grande, Colorado and Great Basin; Pacific Northwest; and California.</p>
		</Term>
		<Term id="Data Series">
			Model condition, simulation, or reach impact output for specified sources, treatments, and regions
			The <em>Data Series</em> specifies what data is drawn on the map.
			The SPARROW model contains many types of data:
			Data used as inputs for the calculations, the result of the calculations, and other types of values coming out of the model.
			<ul>
				<li>Total Instream Flux</li>
                <li>Incremental Flux</li>
                <li>Incremental Yield</li>
                <li>Concentration</li>
                <li>Source Value</li>
                <li>Delivery Fraction</li>
                <li>Incremental Delivered Flux</li>
                <li>Total Delivered Flux</li>
                <li>Incremental Delivered Yield</li>
                <li>Total Standard Err Estimate</li>
                <li>Incremental Standard Err Estimate</li>
			</ul>
		</Term>
		<Term id="Total">
			Takes into account constituent sources upstream and degradation to describe the annual load of the constituent being transported by national surface waters. Units are typically kilograms/year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental">
			Takes into account only sources of the constituent within the surrounding catchment to show local generation of the constituent independent of the upstream load. Units are typically kilograms/year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental Yield">
			Takes into account only sources of the constituent within the surrounding catchment to show the local generation of the constituent normalized for catchment area. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Concentration">
			Total load divided by the long-term average flow of the stream reach. Units are typically kilograms/cubic feet.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Source Value">
			Displays the location and frequency of constituent sources. Units are typically kilograms/year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Delivery Fraction">
			Displays the fraction of incremental load that is delivered to a target reach of interest.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental Delivered Flux">
			Displays the incremental flux generated by a catchment that is delivered to a target reach of interest. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Total Delivered Flux">
			Displays the total flux including sources upstream and within the catchment that is delivered to a target reach of interest. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental Delivered Yield">
			Displays the incremental yield that is delivered to a target reach of interest. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="For Source">
			Choose the constituent source to be assessed.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Comparison">
			Compare the applied treatment output to the 'nominal' SPARROW DSS model conditions.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Nominal">
			The nominal SPARROW DSS model condition is based on source values and streamflow of the model base year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Bins">
			Choose or generate a custom range over which the model output is to be grouped and displayed on the map.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Map Options">
			Choose a map feature for the model output ot be displayed on.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Reach">
			Stream segments that extend between confluence with other streams.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Catchment">
			A watershed that drains to a single stream.
		</Term>
		<Term id="HUC">
			Hydrologic Unit Code
		</Term>
		<Term id="Aggregate Function">
			Calculates the average, maximum, minimum, or sum of the model output when the map displays over HUC.
		</Term>
	</CommonTerms>
</Documentation>
