<Documentation>
	<General/>
	<SPARROW_model>
		<SPARROW_papers>
			<Paper id="paper">
				<Link link="http://water.usgs.gov/nawqa/sparrow/wrr97/results.html"/>
				<Citation_mods>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<genre/>
					<titleInfo>
						<title>SPARROW Surface Water-Quality Modeling Nutrients in Watersheds of the Coterminous United States</title>
					</titleInfo>
					<originInfo>
						<dateOther>1997-01-01 00:00:00.0</dateOther>
						<publisher>Apress</publisher>
						<placeTerm/>
					</originInfo>
					<name>
						<namePart>Smith, R.A., G.E. Schwarz, and R.B. Alexander</namePart>
						<role>Author</role>
					</name>
					<physicalDescription>
						<form/>
						<form/>
						<form/>
					</physicalDescription>
					<note type="citation/reference">Smith, R.A. et al. 1997. SPARROW Surface Water-Quality Modeling Nutrients in Watersheds of the Coterminous United States. Regional interpretation of water-quality monitoring data, Water Resources Research, v. 33, no. 12, pp.2781-2798</note>
					<edition/>
					<languageTerm>ENGLISH</languageTerm>
				</Citation_mods>
			</Paper>
			<Paper id="factsheet">
				<Link link="http://pubs.usgs.gov/fs/2009/3019/pdf/fs_2009_3019.pdf"/>
				<Citation_mods>
					<identifier type="">myid</identifier>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<identifier type=""/>
					<genre/>
					<titleInfo>
						<title>SPARROW MODELING - Enhancing Understanding of the Nation's Water Quality</title>
					</titleInfo>
					<originInfo>
						<dateOther>2009-03-01 00:00:00.0</dateOther>
						<publisher>U.S. Geological Survey</publisher>
						<placeTerm/>
					</originInfo>
					<name>
						<namePart>Preston, S.D., Alexander, R.B., Woodside, M.D., and Hamilton, P.A.</namePart>
						<role>Author</role>
					</name>
					<physicalDescription>
						<form/>
						<form/>
						<form/>
					</physicalDescription>
					<note type="citation/reference">Preston, S.D., Alexander, R.B., Woodside, M.D., and Hamilton, P.A., 2009, SPARROW MODELING-Enhancing Understanding of the Nation's Water Quality: U.S. Geological Survey Fact Sheet 2009-3019, 6 p.</note>
					<edition/>
					<languageTerm>ENGLISH</languageTerm>
				</Citation_mods>
			</Paper>
		</SPARROW_papers>
	</SPARROW_model>
	<CommonTerms>
		<Term id="Adjustments">
			<h2>Adjustments</h2><br/>
			Adjustments allow different management scenarios (changes in model source inputs) 
			to be evaluated with respect to predicted total and incremental flux. Adjustments
			can be made in one of two ways: by adjusting individual reaches or by adjusting groups
			of reaches.<br/>
			<ul>
				<li>To adjust an individual reach's source inputs, first identify the reach on the map.
				You can identify a reach either by clicking on it with the <b>Identify Reach</b> tool
				or by searching for it via the <b>Find a reach...</b> button. Once the reach has been
				identified, navigate to the <b>Model Source Inputs</b> tab, enter the desired input
				values into the <b>Override</b> column, and click <b>Apply</b>.<br/></li>
				<li>To adjust a group of reaches, you must first create an <i>adjustment group</i> 
				of reaches. After identifying a candidate reach on the map, navigate to the 
				<b>Group / Target Membership</b> tab to add it to a group. Once groups are created, 
				right-click the group name on the <b>Adjustments</b> tab and then apply the desired treatments.</li>
			</ul>
		</Term>
		<Term id="Targets">
			<h2>Targets</h2><br/>
			Targets are used to determine the fraction of flux from upstream reaches delivered 
			to a specified downstream reach or water body. To specify a target, identify the 
			desired reach on the map (using the <b>Identify Reach</b> tool) and then navigate 
			to the <b>Group / Target Membership</b> tab. Then check the box labeled <i>Reach is
			a target</i> and click <b>Apply</b>. Alternatively, you may specify targets 
			either individually or all at once using the <b>Find a reach...</b> button.
		</Term>
		<Term id="MRB">
			<p>The US is divided into 8 major river basins: New England and Mid-Atlantic; South Atlantic-Gulf and Tennessee; Great Lakes, Ohio, Upper Mississippi and Souris-Red-Rainy; Missouri; Lower Mississippi, Arkansas-White-Red and Texas-Gulf; Rio Grande, Colorado and Great Basin; Pacific Northwest; and California.</p>
		</Term>
		<Term id="Data Series">
			<h2>Data Series</h2><br/>
			<p>The <i>Data Series</i> specifies what data is drawn on the map.
			The most common model output is the <i>Total Load</i>,
			which is the average amount of the constituent you would expect to
			find in a stream, as predicted by the model.</p>
			
			<p>
				
				
			</p>
			<p>The complete list of data series:</p>
			<!-- This list updated oct 29, 2010 by ee -->
			<ul>
				<li><b>Total Load</b><br/>
					The mean annual load of the constituent (mass per year)
					leaving each stream reach, as predicted by the model. 
					The load reflects the accumulated mass of the constituent 
					contributed by all sources in the total drainage area upstream 
					of the reach outlet. The load includes the effects of in-stream
					attenuation processes in all upstream reaches. 
					The mean annual load is a standardized measure of the constituent
					mass in the stream that reflects the mean quantities of mass
					that are likely to occur during a specified base year under
					long-term mean streamflow conditions. 
					Spatial variations in the standardized loads are generally
					indicative of conditions during higher-flow periods of
					the year that often occur during the winter and spring.  
					The mean annual conditions described by the model 
					predictions also primarily reflect the effects of natural
					and human-related processes that supply and remove 
					constituent mass in watersheds over long time periods. 
					The predicted load is also "unadjusted" for measured 
					stream load values at monitoring sites; measured loads 
					are commonly substituted for model predictions ("adjusted" loads) 
					in the calibration procedure to ensure accurate estimation of the model.
				</li>
                <li><b>Standard Error of Total Load</b><br/>
                	An estimate of the prediction error associated with the <i>Total load</i>, 
                	based on the model calibration.
                	Units are the same as the units for <i>Total load</i>.
                </li>
                <li><b>Incremental Load</b><br/>
					The mean annual load of the constituent (mass per year)
					entering the stream reach from sources in the incremental
					drainage area of the reach.
					The load value reflects the effects of in-stream attenuation
					processes associated with one half of the reach time of travel
					(this assumes that the load at approximately the center of reach on average).
					You can select 'All Sources' or an individual model source to
					map the incremental load for all of the sources together,
					or the theoretical load due to a single source.
                </li>
                <li><b>Standard Error of Incremental Load</b><br/>
					An estimate of the prediction error associated with the <i>Incremental Load</i>,
					based on the model calibration.
					Units are the same as the units for <i>Incremental Load</i>.
				</li>
                <li><b>Incremental Yield</b><br/>
                	The <i>Incremental Load</i> divided by the incremental
                	drainage area of the reach.
                	Units are mass per square kilometer per year.
                </li>
                <li><b>Concentration</b><br/>
                	The average concentration of the constituent in the reach
                	in units of mass per volume.  This is calculated by dividing
                	the <i>Total Load</i> by the <i>Streamflow</i> and converting
                	to a standard unit.
                </li>
                <li><b>Source Value</b><br/>
                	The source value is the amount of a particular source
                	added in the reach's drainage area - you must choose a
                	source to map this data series.  If you have created
                	adjustments as part of a 'what if' scenario, the adjusted
                	source values are presented.<br/>
                	In many cases the 'source' is not a constituent
                	source.  For instance, land area or population could be a source
                	term if it was determined to be a statistically significant
                	surrogate for the constituent.<br/>
                	Also, consider that some source terms may be interdependent.
                	Increasing a hypothetical <i>Agricultural Land Area</i>
                	source value may require decreasing a <i>Developed Land Area</i> source
                	for the set of adjusted reaches.
                </li>
                <li><b>Incremental Area</b><br/>
                	The portion of the area that drains directly to the reach
                	without passing through another reach.
                	This area is independent of the drainage area associated with upstream reaches.
                </li>
                <li><b>Streamflow</b><br/>
                	The mean annual stream flow of the reach, in units of volume per time.
                </li>
                <li><b>Delivery Fraction</b><br/>
                	The fraction of the load leaving a reach that arrives at the
                	downstream end of a selected target reach without any removal
                	by natural attenuation processes
                	(e.g., long-term storage; denitrification).
                	You must choose a target reach if you select this series.
                	<i>This definition may not be correct - isn't the attenuation what the DF actually shows?</i>
                </li>
                <li><b>Incremental Delivered Load</b><br/>
                	The incremental load associated with a stream reach that arrives
                	at the downstream end of a selected target reach, in units
                	of mass per year.
                	You must choose a target reach if you select this series.
                </li>
                <li><b>Total Delivered Load</b><br/>
                	The total load associated with a stream reach that arrives at
                	the downstream end of a selected target reach, in units of mass per year.
                	You must choose a target reach if you select this series.
				</li>
                <li><b>Incremental Delivered Yield</b><br/>
                	The <i>Incremental Delivered Load</i> divided by the drainage
                	area of the reach, in units of mass per square kilometer per year.
                	You must choose a target reach if you select this series.
                </li>
			</ul>
		</Term>
		<Term id="Total">
			Takes into account constituent sources upstream and degradation to describe the annual load of the constituent being transported by national surface waters. Units are typically kilograms/year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental">
			Takes into account only sources of the constituent within the surrounding catchment to show local generation of the constituent independent of the upstream load. Units are typically kilograms/year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental Yield">
			Takes into account only sources of the constituent within the surrounding catchment to show the local generation of the constituent normalized for catchment area. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Concentration">
			Total load divided by the long-term average flow of the stream reach. Units are typically kilograms/cubic feet.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Source Value">
			Displays the location and frequency of constituent sources. Units are typically kilograms/year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Delivery Fraction">
			Displays the fraction of incremental load that is delivered to a target reach of interest.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental Delivered Flux">
			Displays the incremental flux generated by a catchment that is delivered to a target reach of interest. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Total Delivered Flux">
			Displays the total flux including sources upstream and within the catchment that is delivered to a target reach of interest. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Incremental Delivered Yield">
			Displays the incremental yield that is delivered to a target reach of interest. Units are typically kilograms/square kilometer-year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="For Source">
			<h2>Model Source</h2><br/>
			<!--
			Each model has different sources that the modeler has determined to be statistically significant.
			Choose a constituent source from the list to present data only from that source.
			-->
		</Term>
		<Term id="Comparison">
			<h2>Comparison To Nominal Model</h2><br/>
			For the selected <i>Data Series</i>, the model prediction based on your adjusted values
			can be compared to the model prediction based on the original unadjusted values (i.e. the 
			<i>nominal</i> model prediction).<br/>
			Two options are available:
			<ul>
			<li><b>Absolute change from nominal</b> subtracts the
			nominal (unadjusted) model result from the adjusted model result.</li>
			<li><b>% change from nominal</b> presents the percent increase of
			the adjusted model result over the nominal model result.  That is:<br/>
			<code>100 X (adjusted - nominal) / nominal</code><br/>
			Any increase from a nominal value of zero is considered a 100% change.
			Any decrease from a nominal value of zero is considered a -100% change.</li>
			</ul>
		</Term>
		<Term id="Nominal">
			The nominal SPARROW DSS model condition is based on source values and streamflow of the model base year.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Bins">
			<h2>Binning for Map Color and Legend</h2><br/>
			<b>Bins</b> determine how values are grouped and displayed on the map.
			Data are grouped into bins by their values, and data in each bin are
			displayed with a specific color on the map. By modifying the binning
			scheme, you can change the way information is presented on your map.<br/>
			Two auto-generation options are available:
			<ul>
			<li><b>Equal Count</b> attempts to construct bins such that an equal
			number of data values fall within each bin.  Because the values
			are sometimes clustered, it is often not possible to generate bins
			with an even distribution of values into each bin.</li>
			<li><b>Equal Range</b> constructs bins such that each bin has an
			equal numerical interval or range.</li>
			</ul>
			If you check <b>Use automatic binning</b>, SPARROW DSS will choose a binning scheme for you
			based on the map options you have selected. The recommended binning will consist of 5 bins of
			either equal count or equal range. To specify a custom binning scheme, or to edit colors,
			uncheck this option and click on the <b>Edit Custom Bins...</b> button.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Map Options">
			Controls basic features of how the map is rendered.
			Click the headings of the subsections for more information on each feature.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Reach">
			Stream segments that extend between confluence with other streams.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Catchment">
			A watershed that drains to a single stream.
		</Term>
		<Term id="HUC">
			Hydrologic Unit Code
		</Term>
		<Term id="Aggregate Function">
			Calculates the average, maximum, minimum, or sum of the model output when the map displays over HUC.
		</Term>
		<Term id="Reaches Or Catchments">
			<h2>Display Reaches or Catchments</h2><br/>
			Selecting <b>Reaches</b> will draw individual reach lines (water bodies) on the map.
			Selecting <b>Catchments</b> will draw each catchment region (land area surrounding each reach).
			In both cases, the color used to render the reach or catchment is based
			on the binning scheme selected on the <b>Map Controls</b> tab.
		</Term>
	</CommonTerms>
</Documentation>
